威廉·施萬克·吉爾伯特(英國著名劇作家) 寫道 "愛讓世界轉動"
W.s.gilbert wrote, "it's love that makes the world go 'round."
如果這是真的 那Haley的世界 就旋轉得稍快了一些
And if that's true, then the world spun a little faster with haley in it.
從高中時代起 Haley就是我最好的朋友
Haley was my best friend since we were in high school.
我們確實有過不快 但如果還有一件事 能讓我們彼此無條件認同
We certainly had our struggles, but if there's one thing we agreed on unconditionally,
那就是對我們兒子Jack的愛和責任
It was our love and commitment to our son jack.
Haley對Jack的愛 是快樂而無畏的
Haley's love for jack was joyous and fierce.
可正是這種無畏 讓她不能站在我們中間
That fierceness is why she isn't here today.
母愛是自然界中至高無上的力量
A mother's love is an unrivaled force of nature.
Haley的行為讓我們獲益良多
And we can all learn much from the way haley lived her life.
Haley的死 讓我們每個人停下腳步 回首自己的人生
Haley's death causes each of us to stop and take stock of our lives.
審視我們是怎樣的人 審視我們走過的路
To measure who we are and what we've become.
關於自身 我還沒有全部答案 但我瞭解Haley的為人
I don't have all those answers for myself, but i know who haley was.
為了保護我們共同孕育的孩子 她勇於犧牲
She was the woman who died protecting the child we brought into this world together.
Jack長大後 我一定會讓他明白 她的母親是個怎樣的人
And i will make sure that jack grows up knowing who his mother was
她是如何愛他 保護他 讓他明白我有多麼愛她
And how she loved and protected him and how much i loved her.
如果Haley今天在這 她會希望我們 不要哀悼她的死亡 而是緬懷她的人生
If haley were with us today, she would ask us not to mourn her death but to celebrate her life.
她會告訴我們...
She would tell us...
她會告訴我們要無條件地熱愛家庭
She would tell us to love our families unconditionally...
和他們緊緊擁抱在一起 因為到頭來 這才是最重要的事
And to hold them close, because in the end, they are all that matter.
我們是在高中音樂劇 試演中相遇的(吉爾伯特的著名輕歌劇)
I met haley at the tryouts of our high school's production of "the pirates of penzance."
前幾天晚上 我找到了當時演出的拷貝 獨自看著
I found our copy of the play and was looking through it the other night,
發現有一段歌詞
And i came upon a passage that seemed...
似乎很合適在此刻朗讀
Appropriate for this moment.
"喔 擦乾晶瑩的眼淚 它如露珠般流過堅毅的臉龐"
"oh, dry the glistening tear "that dews that martial cheek.
"聽著 可愛的孩子 你從中探尋著安慰"
"thy loving children hear, "in them thy comfort seek.
"帶著同情與關懷 他們的胳膊環繞你 撫摸著"
"with sympathetic care "their arms around thee creep,
"為了 他們無法承受的父親的淚光"
"for, oh, they cannot bear to see their father weep."
放下吧
Ok, you can go ahead.
給媽媽一個飛吻
Blow mommy a kiss.
- 如果有什麼我可以幫忙的... - 謝謝
- If there's anything i can do... - Thank you.
- 節哀順變 - 謝謝你 Gina 謝謝你能來
- I'm so sorry for your loss. - Thank you, gina. Thank you for coming.
我想你應該需要透透氣
I think you could use some air.
- Jack沒事了 我看見他和表兄弟們一起 - 嗯
- Jack's ok. I saw him with his cousins. - Ok.
Jessica 你能幫Jack拿些吃的嗎?
Jessica, would you make sure that jack gets something to eat?
- 當然 - 我馬上回來 謝謝
- Sure. - And i'll be right back. Thanks.
我們應該做些什麼?
What do we do?
我們幫不上什麼 只能等他自己平復心情
There's nothing we can do. We just gotta wait him out.
你們覺得他會回來嗎?
You think he'll ever come back?
- 是你會嗎? - 他會回來的
- Would you? - He'll come back.
只是不知道當他回來時 會是什麼樣子
I just don't know what he's gonna look like when he does.
當他準備回來的時候 我們只需要在那埵u候著
We just need to be there for him when he's ready.
我沒能遵守對Haley的承諾
You know, i broke my promise to haley.
什麼承諾?
What promise?
我告訴她我會抓住Foyet
I told her that i would catch foyet and that i'd...
然後用我剩餘的生命來補償她
Spend the rest of my life making it up to her.
你依然可以 你救了Jack
You still can. You saved jack.
你知道 可能我幹這行有一套
You know, i may have the tools to do this job,
可不知道 幫助兒子 我是不是也有一套
But i don't know if i have the tools to help my son.
問問你自己 想成為怎樣的父親
You have to ask yourself what kind of father you want to be.
當你明白這點的時候
And when you figure that out...
你就知道該怎麼做了
Then you'll know what to do.
我今天說的話是認真的 生活改變了
I meant what i said today. Things have changed.
我必須為Jack作出最好的安排
And i need to do what's best for jack.
你會的
You will.
他們不該召集我們 不能是今晚
They can't be calling us in, not tonight.
我跟他們說說
I'm on it.
我們不能離開
We can't go.
我們必須走了 我去叫Rossi
We have to. I'll get rossi.
和Strauss談談 讓她派另一隊去吧
Talk to strauss, tell her to send another team.
其它小組都在執行任務
There's no other team available.
納什維爾需要我們
Nashville's calling us in.
兩周之內出現了第二具屍體 連著兩個星期五晚上都有人被殺
Second body in 2 weeks, both killed on consecutive friday nights.
他們知道時間緊迫 希望我們能發現一些線索
They realize they're up against the clock and they're hoping we might find something they didn't.
兄弟們 抱歉 可是我們剛接到通知
Guys. I'm sorry, but we just got called in.
- 我們必須走了 - 需要什麼給我打電話
- We have to go. - Call me if you need anything.
- 照顧好你兒子 - 謝謝
- Take care of your son. - Thanks.
你會好起來吧?
You gonna be ok?
等你回來我們再見吧
I'll see you when you get back.
犯罪心理 第五季 第10集
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode10 The Slave of Duty
"我們所愛的地方是家 即使人離開了 心依然牽掛著"
"where we love is home-- "home that our feet may leave, but not our hearts."
Oliver Wendell Holmes (美國著名法學家 最高法院大法官)
Oliver wendell holmes.
兩周內死了兩位女性 都死在家中 沒有破門而入的跡象
Two women dead in two weeks, both killed in their own homes, and no sign of forced entry.
地上鋪滿了玫瑰花瓣
Floors were covered in rose petals.
很浪漫啊 有被性侵犯的證據嗎?
Quite the romantic. Evidence of sexual assault?
沒有 兩人最後被看見都是週五晚上 離開辦公室
None.Both women were last seen leaving their offices on a friday
週一沒有再回去上班
and never showed up to work on a monday.
現在已經週四了 為什麼這麼晚才叫我們去?
It's thursday. Why are we only being called in now?
第二具屍體昨天才被發現的
The second body was only found yesterday.
這堣]許有著社會經濟學模式
There may be a socio-economic pattern emerging.
第一位受害人Bethany Heminger 住在Belle Meade區
The first victim, bethany heminger, lived in belle meade, melissa johnson in brentwood.
Melissa Johnson住在Brentwood 都在富人區
Both are affluent neighborhoods.
兩家都沒有被盜跡象
Yet there was nothing missing from either home.
她們的工作是什麼?
What did these women do for a living?
Bethany是位辯護律師 Melissa是公司主管
Bethany was a defense attorney, melissa a corporate executive.
兩人都是深褐色頭髮 有著相似的外貌特徵 和很高的職業地位
Two brunettes with similar features in high-powered professions?
這不是偶然的
That's not a coincidence.
這些女性很可能象徵著他認識的某個人
These women most likely represent someone he knows.
我們要弄清不明嫌犯是在哪 遇見這些受害人的
All right, so we need to figure out where this unsub is meeting his victims
又是怎麼進入她們家的
And how he's gaining access to their homes.
如果他按照這個模式來 很有可能他已經選好了下一個目標
And if he's staying on pattern, Most likely this guy has picked out his next target.
我們應該查一下花匠 家政人員 泳池服務員
We should check gardeners, housekeeping staff, pool attendants,
花店人員 看下有沒有同時在兩家工作的
Floral shops, see if anyone worked both homes.
列一個跟蹤表 Garcia
Start working up a paper trail, garcia.
看看這些女人在哪被盯上的
Find out where these women were in the days leading up to each murder.
阿拉丁神燈 我鑽回去啦
Like a genie in a bottle--poof!
Prentiss 你跟我去看下Johnson的犯罪現場
All right. Prentiss, you and i are gonna go check out the johnson crime scene.
Rossi 你跟Reid跟驗屍官談下 開始被害者研究
Rossi, you and reid talk to the coroner, start working up victimology.
JJ 找她們家人和同事談談 看看能不能找到我們能用的聯繫
Jj, talk to the families and staff and find a connection we can use.
我知道大家都在擔心Hotch
I understand that all of our thoughts are with hotch.
但是現在我需要大家都 把精力放在案子上
But right now, i need us all to focus on this case.
不明嫌犯再次作案前 我們還有不到一天的時間
We have less than a day before this unsub will strike again.
讓我們快點把這案子結了吧
Let's finish this thing fast.
田納西州 納什維爾
******
你跟定就是FBI的人了 我是Landon Kaminski
You must be the fbi. Landon kaminski.
Jareau探員 我們通過電話
Agent jareau. We spoke on the phone.
真高興你們來 市長可逼著我呢
Yeah, it's nice to meet you. The mayor's on my ass.
兩位傑出女性在我的轄區內被殺 大家都知道 得準備好有第三個受害者
Two prominent women killed on my watch and everyone knows we're bracing for a third.
我們希望那不會發生 我們在哪兒佈置起來?
Well, let's hope that doesn't happen. Where would you like us to set up?
這兒
In here.
我需要向媒體發佈一份聲明
I'm gonna need to issue a statement with the press.
納什維爾的每個女性 都該知道有個連環殺手在逃
Every woman in nashville needs to know there's a serial killer on the loose.
我們需要她們採取預防措施 以免成為兇手的下一個目標
We need them taking preventative measures to avoid becoming his next target.
市長覺得我們應該盡量精確
The mayor thinks we should be as specific as possible.
每一位女性 探長
Every woman, detective.
他的前兩個受害者可能 來自同一個社會階層
His first 2 victims may be from the same social class,
但如果我們這麼快就把受害人群隔離
But if we isolate victimology this soon,
可能會導致兇手 跨出自己的習慣作案範圍
It may cause him to go outside of his own comfort zone,
這樣就更難追蹤他了
And then he'll be even harder to track.
最好加強警覺 把他和 所有可能的受害者徹底隔離 你覺得呢?
Better to stress hypervigilance and shut down his victim pool completely, don't you think?
好的 長官
Yes, ma'am.
這房子有保安系統
Well, the house has a security system,
但她的朋友說 她只在出城的時候才用
But her friends say that she only used it when she traveled out of town.
他殺了狗 把它藏在車庫的儲藏室
He killed the dog, hid it in a storage container in the garage.
她可能認為他是正當防衛
She probably thought he was protection enough.
那是她第一個錯誤
That was her first mistake.
她擁有所有預防兇手入室的措施 只是沒有合理運用
She had all the precautions to avoid home invasion, she just didn't use them properly.
這些指紋與另一犯罪現場的指紋吻合
These are the prints that match the other crime scene.
看起來他並不介意 把它們弄得到處都是
It looks like he didn't hesitate to get them everywhere.
這顯然表明 他非常混亂
Which typically would indicate that he's disorganized.
可這個現場 卻處處體現著條理
This crime scene screams of organization.
玫瑰花 那狗
The roses, the dog.
對這女人來說 他是個陌生人
He was a stranger to these women.
他沒有匆忙行動 而是早有準備
He didn't talk his way in, he was laying in wait.
而且他知道 系統堥S有他的指紋
And he knew his prints wouldn't show up in the system.
他沒有前科 這意味著他很聰明 很有可能受過教育
He had no priors, which means he was smart and most likely educated.
他很清楚自己在做什麼 並確保自己有足夠的時間完成
This guy knew exactly what he was doing and he made sure he had enough time to do it.
所以 他知道她什麼時候離開家 什麼時候回來
So, he knew when she'd leave the house and when she'd return.
他在跟蹤她們
He's stalking them.
大門外側把手上只有受害者的指紋
It's only the victim's prints on the exterior doorknobs.
窗戶上啥也沒有 車庫也沒有強行進入的痕跡
Nothing on the windows, the garage wasn't forced.
那他怎麼進來的呢?
So how did he get in?
兩名女性身上都有防禦傷
Defensive wounds on both women.
最近受害者的防禦傷多一些
More so on the latest victim.
她竭力反抗
She fought back the hardest.
沒有捆綁痕跡 她們沒有被捆起來
No ligature marks. They weren't bound.
那他怎麼阻止她們逃跑呢?
So how does he keep them from running out?
也許他堵住了所有逃跑路線 或者 拿把刀威脅就足夠了
Maybe he blocked the escape route, or maybe the threat of a knife was enough.
這一點我倒是挺清楚
I might be able to answer that.
- 刀刺傷不是唯一的傷處 - 什麼意思?
- The stab wounds weren't the only injuries. - What do you mean?
Melissa Johnson有腦震盪
Melissa johnson had a concussion.
Bethany Heminger有一根肋骨骨折
Bethany heminger, a broken rib.
他毆打她們 證明自己才是主宰 讓她們害怕到不敢嘗試逃跑
Annitial assault to prove his domince, make sure they're too scared to try and escape.
還有點東西你們得看看
Something else you should see.
兩個受害人的胃部殘留物都一樣
Both their stomach contents were theame.
雞肉 西蘭花 意大利面 沙拉 和紅酒
Chicken, broccoli, pasta, salad, and red wine.
他是在實施自己的幻想
He's playing out a fantasy.
在這個幻想 他掌控一切
One he has to control.
他用花瓣 美酒佈置現場 還給她們做吃的
He sets the scene with flower petals and wine and then he cooks for them.
她們最後的晚餐
Their last supper.
他做飯 之後又收拾乾淨
So he cooked, and he cleaned up after himself.
卻唯獨留下這些花瓣?
Why did he leave the petal trail?
這對不明嫌犯來說 一定意義重大
It's gotta mean something our guy.
他不止是重溫幻想 更在不斷重複
He's not just reliving a fantasy, he's repeating it.
一樣的步驟 一樣的食物
It's the same routine, the same meal.
這不只是簡單的步驟 而是妥善的禮儀
It's not just routine, it's proper etiquette.
- 什麼? - 看下這個
- What? - Take a look at this.
椅子後側中部 有個手印
There's a handprint in the center back of this chair right here.
他是為自己挪的這椅子
He pulled this chair out for himself.
而這張椅子呢 手印在兩邊
Over here, there are handprints on either side of the chair.
他為她拉開椅子 為她倒酒...
He pulled this chair out for her, poured her wine...
吃完後 甚至還一一清理
And even cleaned up after the meal was done.
- 但到了這 有些改變 - 他讓她洗澡
- But up here something changed. - Then he drew her a bath.
Messa Johnson就是在這被殺的
And this is where messa johnson was murdered.
這是幻想終結的地方
This is where the fantasy ended.
因為她打破了幻想麼?
Because she broke it?
- 要我肯定會 - 什麼意思?
- I would. - What do you mean?
在樓下第一次被襲擊後 沒錯 我是害怕了
Well, after the initial asult downstairs, fine, i'm scared,
但仍會尋找機會逃跑
But i'm still looking for another chance to escape.
晚餐 美酒 佳餚
Dinner, wine, dishes.
沒有近在眼前的生命危險 可以從容不迫 等待時機
I'm not in any immediate danger, so i c take my time, wait for the right momt.
我按他的吩咐來 是不想再被他傷害
I do what he says because i don't want him to hurt me again.
但當他把我帶來這堮 我處於最勢單力薄的情境
But once he gets me in here, i am at my most vulnerable.
於是恐懼壓過理智 拚命一搏
So fear takes over and e fights back.
因為如果她不搏...
Because if she doesn't...
家應該是安身處
Home is where you're suosed to feel safe.
怎麼能被奪走安全
Nobody deserves to have that taken away.
對了 踢進去!
All right, right in there!
嘿 小鬼 PJs動畫開始了哦
Hey, buddy, it time for pjs.
我能再看一次嗎?
Can i watch one more time?
我在等媽咪過來
I'm waiting for mommy.
好了 準備好許願了嗎?
All right, ready to make a wish. Ok.
1... 2...
好棒哦! 生日快樂 說'嗨 爸爸'
Nice job! Ok. Happy birthday. Say, hi, daddy.
嗨 爸爸
Hi, daddy.
- 我們親他一口 - 我也想她
- let's give him a big kiss. - I miss her, too.
我能再在你房間睡覺嗎?
Can i sleep in your ro again?
當然可以了
Sure.
好的 來吧
ok, come on.
有什麼發現沒?
Find anything?
這兩處房子 都有好幾個人能進出
Several people hadccess to each home.
管家 園丁 泳池清潔工 遛狗人員 每個人都配有鑰匙 而且都有不在場證據
Housekeeper, gardener, pool cleaner, dog walker, each with their n key and an alibio match.
- 有交叉點嗎? - 絲毫沒有
- Any cross-over? - None.
我們甚至調查了快遞員和公共服務人員
We even vetted delivery people anutility workers.
Garcia 你有發現麼?
Garcia, do you have anything?
系統堻s指紋的影子都查不到
There's no hits on the prints at all,
我按Derek長官的吩咐 建了一份書面追蹤記錄
But i did wh sir derek there asked and i created a paper trail.
謀殺案前的所有時間 兩名受害者間都沒有交集
There's no crossver between the two victims themlves in the wee leading up to their murders,
- 但她們所處的圈子很類似 - 什麼意思?
- But they did run in similar circles. - How do you mean?
她們都是鄉村俱樂部的會員 但分屬於不同的俱樂部
They both have cntry club memberships, though to different clubs.
她們都去高檔的餐廳 參加私人音樂會 住豪華酒店
They went to upscale restaurants, private concert venues, posh hotels.
她們享受著奢華誇張的生活方式 相當燒錢
They enjoyed a high-class, highfalutin lifestyle, an expensive one.
他一下就能融入那種生活方式
A lifestyle he'd fit right into.
這男人受過教育 聰明 正派
This g is educated, intelligent, proper.
是個十足的紳士
He's a downright gentleman.
玫瑰花瓣清楚地說明這一點
The rose petals sent a pretty specific message.
不管她們願不願意 他都和她們玩浪漫
He's romancinghem whether they want it or not.
他有這方面的社交技能
He's got the social skills to back it up.
嘿 Garcia 查一下約會服務和社交網站
Hey, garcia, take a look at dating services and social networking sites.
查找專業人員和富家子弟
Look for working professionals and privilegedlite.
核對 核對 再核對 一無所獲
Check, check, and checkers. Back in a smidge.
我們需要更多資料
We need more.
我們搞明白他是怎麼進屋的了嗎?
Have we figured out how he's getting into these homes?
到處都沒有強行進入的痕跡
No sign of forced entry anywhe.
但是他仍能在遇害者下班回家之前 早早地進入屋子
Yet he's sti gaining access to their homes long before the victims ever get home from work.
因為他需要時間做飯 佈置現場
I mean, this guy needs timeo cook and set up his scene.
他要麼有鑰匙 要麼就有穿牆術
He's either got a key or he can move through walls.
我們得用新的眼光看問題
We need fresh eyes.
好了 聽著 所有人回酒店休息下
T, listen . I want everybody to go back to the hotel And try to get some rest.
我們明天早上繼續
We're gonna have to pick this up again in the morning.
- 這就放棄了? - 不是 我們休息一下
- We're giving up? - No. We're gonna take a break.
明天早班我們要給出側寫 葬禮到現在還沒人合過眼
We have to give the profile at morning roll and none of us has slept nce the funeral.
一旦Garcia能給出書面追蹤記錄 我們就能把網撒得廣一些
Once garcia can get us a paper trail, then we can expand our canvass.
在那之前 我們沒什麼能做的
Till then ere's really not a lot we can do.
你能關掉音樂嗎?
Would you please turn the music off?
但這是你最喜歡的歌
But it's your farite song.
你怎麼知道的?
How do you know that?
這是你iPod媦蔗韘蜈く怞h的歌曲
It's the most playedong on your ipod.
不! 不! 不!
No! No!
別亂跑
Stop it.
你把氣氛給毀了
You're ruining it.
對不起 我不跑了 求你了
I'sorry. I won't do it again. Ease.
我會按你的吩咐做
I'll do whever you want.
我花了好多時間和精力 準備這個與眾不同的夜晚
ve put a lot of time and effort into making this a special night.
要你欣賞就那麼難嗎?
Is it too much to ask for a little appreciation?
對不起 我不會再跑了 求你了
I'm sorry. I won't do it again. Please.
我會聽你的吩咐
I'll do whatever you wan.
好吧 我原諒你
that'sok.I forgive you.
小誤會 對吧?
A little misunderstanding, right?
是的 沒錯
Yes. That's right.
我會忘記剛才的事
I'll just forget all about this.
是的 求你了
Yes, please.
現在...
Now...
你該洗澡了
I think it's t for your bath.
Jack 聽著 我要你想好 把玩具放哪堨h 好嗎?
Ok, jack, listen, i want you to figure out where you want to put all your toys, ok?
- 好的 爸爸 - 好的 乖寶貝
- Ok, daddy. - Alright, sweet boy.
Strauss主任 感謝你能過來
Chief strauss, i appreciate your coming to me.
噢 沒事 這關頭總不能讓你離開你兒子
Oh, of course. This isn't a time for you to be away from your son.
請進
Come in.
Jack 能和Strauss主任打招呼嗎?
Jack, can you say llo to chief strauss?
嗨 Jack
Hi, jack.
請坐
Have a seat.
那麼 你怎麼樣?
So, how are you holding up?
- 我還好 - Jack怎麼樣?
- I'm ok. - And how's jack?
他還過得去 我覺得他還不明白所有的事情
He's coping. I don't think he fully understands everything that's going on.
得了 他怎麼會全明白呢?
Oh, right, well, how could he?
小雪人大行動 (動畫電影)...
Knick knack...
你說有事找我商量?
You said that there was something you wanted to discuss with me?
是的
Yes, i do.
這是要我退休
Thiss retirement.
我已經和上頭商量過了
I've talked with the director.
出了這樣的事 你不一定非得回來工作
Given the circumstances, there's no reason you should have to return to the bureau.
我們可以提供全額退休金和福利待遇
We can offer you full pension and benefits.
你是要我離開局媔?
Are saying that you want me to leave the bau?
當然這還是由你來決定 不過 我這是給你條路
Well, obviously that's your choice, but i'm offering you a way out.
Morgan探員的升職只是暫時的 不過他的表現超出了我們的預期
Agent moan's protion was temporary, but he's exceeded our expectations,
如果你決定退位 我也有能力讓他待在這個位子上
And i'm confident that i could make it permanent, if you decide to step down.
隊員們既可以團結一致 你也可以多陪陪你兒子
The team would be together and you could be with your son.
要我什麼時候作出決定?
And when would you like a decision?
我想你現在就答覆我
I thought i would be leavi with one.
你還有什麼可猶豫的呢?
What's your hesitation?
我只想把所有選擇都好好考慮下
I would just like to weigh all of my options.
那也行
Whatever you need.
我們認為不明嫌犯 已經找到下一個受害人了
We believe our unsub is already th his next victim.
如果他符合我們側寫的類型 受害人就應該是事業成功型女性
If he matches pattern, she'll be a successful woman,
很可能是深褐色頭髮 30歲出頭到40多歲
Probably brunette, early 30s to mid-40s.
她應該住在納什維爾的高檔區
She'll be at home in nashville's upper echelon.
也就是說 他能融入這個社區
This mea that he fits in.
他會開高檔的車 穿高檔的衣服 智力超群
Herives the right car, he wears the right clothes, he's highly intelligent.
很可能有點社會地位
He probably comes fr a place of status.
這個人善於交際 討人歡心
This guy's sociable, and he's endearing.
讓你永遠想不到他會殺人
You would never suspect that this man is capable of murder.
但他會不惜任何代價重溫自己的幻想
But he will do whatever it takes to protect the fantasy that he's trying to relive.
就是這個幻想給了他動力
It's this fantasy which fuels his drive.
他重現了一個浪漫的夜晚 並和每個受害人共同參與
He's recreating a romantic evening and repeating it with each of his victims.
很有可能他最近剛結束了一段感情
He most likely recently had a relationship taken away from him.
所以我們應該關注下那些最近 剛痛失愛人或離婚的男性
So look at men who have lost loved ones or have gone through a messy divorce.
不過和Bundy一樣 這些女性受害人 只代表了他真實生活中痛失的女性
But like bundy, these women are representations of that first loss.
Bundy選中的女性都擁有和 當初拋棄他的女人一樣的特徵
Bundy picked victims who had similar features to the woman that abandoned him,
所以我們認為 這個不明嫌犯也是一樣
And we believe that our unsub is doing the exact same thing.
這些女性都是自信堅強的成功女性 她們會反抗
These women were cfident, successful, and strong, and they fought back.
既然不名嫌犯能輕易控制住她們 他一定很有手段
Which means he has the ability to overpower them fairly easily.
他認為或幻想自己和她們處於愛戀中
He believes or fantasizes he's in a relationship with these woman.
不論他們最初的相識是多麼短暫 對他來說都很重要
No matter how fleeting the initial interaction is, it's everything to him.
也就是一次邀約
An invitation.
我們的技術分析師 已經搜集了一些地點
Our technical analyst has compiled a list of locations
受害人在死前可能去過的
that the victims visited prior toheir death.
都是些高檔場所
These are high-class establishments.
我們也要去調查下這些地方
We're going to want to visit the same places.
看有沒有男的符合側寫 有沒有女性符合受害人的類型
So, look for men who fit the profile, but also women who match victimology.
如果有人特別引人注意 就找來談談
If somebody's been paying a little too much attention to them, talk to them.
問下名字 記下來 我們再回來查
Get a read, then jot tir name down so that we can check them out.
好了 夥計們 整理下自己要查的地方 都行動起來
All right, folks, pick up your canvassing assignments and get to work.
謝謝
Thank you.
納什維爾連環殺手 專對成功女性下手
******
今天會放晴
The rain's supposed to clear up today.
將近60度呢
It's gonna be in the high 50s.
你今天要做什麼呢?
What do you want to do today?
綠山商場在放些不錯的電影
There are a lot of good movies pling at the green hills mall.
要不要去看一下?
You want to go see something?
今天在家待著怎麼樣?
Why don't we stay inside today?
看個片子什麼的
Maybe watch a dvd.
我想和你來個真正的約會 Joe
I want to go on a real da, joe.
我以為...
I thought...
昨晚親熱之後 你就該知道你對我有多重要了
After we made love last night, you'd realize how much you mean to me.
你難道不相信我嗎 Joe?
Don't you trust me, joe?
- 誰來了? - 我不知道
- Who's that? - I have no idea.
Erika? 親愛的 是我! 你在嗎?
Erika? Honey, it's me! You home?
想給我個驚喜嗎 寶貝兒?
Got a surprise for me, baby?
Erika?
Grant 救我!
Grant, help!
為什麼你會有鑰匙?
Why do you have a key?
快跑!
Run!
上樓! 跑 跑 跑 跑 跑!
Get upstairs! Go, go, go, go, go!
Grant! Grant!
為 什 麼 你 有 鑰 匙?
Why--do--you--have--a--key?
不! Grant! 不要! Grant! 不!
No! Grant! No! Grant! No!
嘿 Erika 甜心...
Hey, erikasweetie...
為什麼他會有鑰匙?
Why did he have a key?
房主是Erika Silverman 國際設計公司的項目經理
house belongs to an erika silverman, project director in an international design firm.
男性受害人 應該是她的男友Grant Franklin
We're assuming the male victim is her boyiend grant franklin.
- 還有男性受害人? - 他們兩個都被傷得很嚴重
- Male victim? - They're both pretty beat up.
要牙醫記錄才能最後確定身份
We'll need dental records for a positive i.d.
- 是誰發現的? - UPS的快遞
- Who called it in? - Ups guy.
要她簽收個包裹 發現門大開著 我們帶他出去了
Needed her to sign for a package, the door was wide open. We got him out back.
JJ 你去和他談談
Jj, talk to him.
Erika Silverman的屍體呢?
Where's erika silverman's body?
他改變了自己的慣用手法
He changed his m. O.
臉部和頸部多處刺傷
Multiple stab wounds to the face and neck.
典型的過度殺人
Classic overkill.
有證據表明她死之前有過性行為
And evidence that she had sex before she died.
強迫的還是自願的?
Forced or consensual?
沒有證據是性侵犯
No evidence of sexual assault.
她陪他演下去了
She played along.
她和不明嫌犯發生性行為 她想這樣就不會死
She had sex th the unsub because she thought it would keep her alive.
那為什麼會這樣?
So why didn't it?
這次殺人帶有憤怒和針對個人的情緒
This kill is personal, angry.
他想要的東西她沒能全部給他
She didn't give him everything that he wanted.
他要的還不夠多麼?
What else does he want?
昨晚吃飯的餐具洗過了 但早餐盤卻沒有
The dinner dishes are washed, but the breakfast plates aren't.
他這次沒有收拾乾淨
He didn't cln up this time.
男友的出現肯定讓他很震驚 打亂了他計劃
The boyfriend must have surprised him and disrupted his routine.
我不太明白 我覺得他差不多都做完了
I don't know, i'd say he came pretty close to finishing it.
看上去他們看了電影 吃了個早餐
It looks like they watched aovie, had an early breakfast.
她整晚都和他在一起
She was with him all night.
- 嘿 Garcia - 壞消息 美人
- Hey, garcia. - Bad news, buttercup.
好的 是什麼?
Great. What is it?
社交網站記錄上沒有什麼支出
No payoff on the social networng sites,
這個Erika Silverman也沒有任何的不良記錄
and this erika silverman rson does not leave a breadcrumb-like trail.
除了一些網購信息和自動生成的賬戶支出
Aside from a couple of online purchases and some automatic debits,
她整一周都沒用過她的信用卡
she hasn't used her credit card all week.
好的 謝謝
All right. Thanks.
嘿 Garcia找不到這一周來有關 Erika Silverman下落的信息
O, garcia couldn't find anything about erika silverman's whereabouts over the past week.
沒去購物 沒去餐廳 什麼都沒有
No stores, no restaurants, nothing.
沒準還有別的辦法知道她去了哪
Thermay actually be another way to figure out where she's been.
知道受害者的車都去哪了麼?
Do we know where any of the victims' cars are?
據我所知都扣起來了
As far as i know, they're in impound.
- 咱得查查那4輛車 - 4輛?
- We need access to all 4 of them. - 4?
還得查Grant Franklin的車
We should also get grant franklin's car.
他可能開車載Erika去了什麼地方 然後遇見了兇手
He may have driven erika somewhere where she met the unsub.
******
在對受害者的分析中我們肯定漏掉了什麼
There has to be something in the victimology.
當時如果不是Grant Franklin正好回家 Erika現在可能還活著
If grant franklin hadn't come home when he did, ika would probably still be alive.
那麼兇手怎麼可能忽略了他呢?
So how did the unsub miss him?
上面說他上周去印第安納波利斯 看望家人了
It says he was out of town last week visiting family in indianapolis.
可下手如此兇狠 表明兩個受害者他都認識
Still, the violence of those kills indicates he knew both victims.
因為受害者和兇手待的時間越長 他下手的時候就越狠
'Cause the longer victims are with theiller, the more desperate the attack.
兇手在Erika Silverman臉上劃了17刀
The unsub stabbed erika silverman 17 times in the face,
在Grant Franklin臉上和生殖器上捅了34刀
grant franklin 34 times to the face and genitals.
很好理解 計劃得越周詳 越會花時間在上面
It makes sense. The more he perfects his routine, he more invested he becomes.
Kaminski警官 你的人找到受害者 最後去過的地方了麼?
Detective kaminski, have your men had any luck canvassing the victims' last known whereabouts?
沒有 我打算晚上就讓他們撤了
None. I'm thinking of pulling them off for the night.
- 這可不行 - 為什麼? 受害人已經死了
- That's a mistake. - Why is that? The vic's dead.
如果他按他的模式來的話 等他下次行動我們還有一周的時間
If he sticks to the pattern, we've got another week before he strikes again.
因為他以前沒得到過這麼多
Because he's never gotten this far before.
他極度需要再一次實現他的幻想
He's desperate to ay out his fantasy.
到了這一步 他可不會按行動時間表來了
A man like this isn't gonna stick to any timetle.
他今晚就會再次行動
He's gonna try to finish this tonight.
JJ 你去開發佈會 縮小受害者範圍
Jj, we need you on the news. Narrow victimology.
告訴大家他仍然逍遙法外
Let people know that he's out there right now.
沒問題
I'm on it.
我們還是不能確定 他是怎麼找上受害者的
We still don't know where he's finding his victims.
但我們知道 Erika Silverman住在Green Hills
But we do know that erika silverman lived in green hills.
這樣就有了三個點 我們可以定位容易下手的區域了
That's 3 points and we finally have our geographical comfort zone.
也就是說 兇手就在這個區域的某個地方
It's a good bet the unsub lis somewhere in this area,
而Erika就是我們找出 他們在哪相遇的關鍵
And erika is our key to figuring out where they met.
噢 天 晚餐吃薄烤餅 還能有更好的嗎?
Oh, man, pancakes for dinner. Is there anything better?
不 沒有
No, ere's not.
嘿 Jack 這些人是誰?
Hey, jack, who are these guys?
這是你 這是壞人 他們在打架
This is you, and this is the bad guy. They're fighting.
那誰贏了 Jack?
Who wins, jack?
爸爸 沒人能戰勝我老爸
Daddy. No one beats daddy.
嘿 Jack Jessica阿姨差不多要做好飯了
Hey, jack. Aunt jessica's almost got dinner ready.
你告訴我 我們吃飯前該怎麼做?
I forgot, what do we do before we eat?
- 洗手 - 很好 去吧
- Wash our hands. - good job.Come on.
爸爸...
Daddy...
他自己想像出的那些 但願沒什麼問題
He built those himself. I hope it's ok.
當然
Of course.
聽著 我很感謝你過來
Listen, i really appreciate your coming over.
幫助和支持我們 實在是太好了
All your help and support, it's been great.
他是我的侄子 你是我的家人
He's my nephew, and you're my family.
只要你需要 我就來幫忙
I'll be here as much as you want.
局媗我退休
The bureau has offered me retirement.
那你怎麼說?
What did you tell them?
你知道 Jack比以前更需要我
You know, jack needs me now more than ever.
也就是說必須全天候在這兒
That means being here full-time.
Haley跟我分開之後 他沒怎麼跟我在一起 這很讓人難過
After haley and i were apart, he didn't havee very much, and that was hard,
但我知道他至少還有他媽媽 而現在 他正需要的是爸爸
I knew that at least he had his mom and right now he really needs his dad.
當然 Aaron
Ofourse he does, aaron.
你我都知道 你和Haley分開 並不是因為不再愛對方
We both know you and haley didn't separate beuse you stopped loving each other.
是工作成了個中阻礙
Your job just got in the way.
你的團隊需要你 即使讓你退休 他們還是需要你
Your team needed you, and despite this offer, i doubt that's changed.
或許你根本不用退休
Maybe you don't need to retire.
如果你不在的時候 我留下來照顧Jack呢?
What if i stayed with jack when you had to be away?
Jessica 我很感激你...
Jessica, i appreciate that...
拜託...
Please...
對我來說 讓我照顧Jack 也很重要
It would mean a lot to me if you'd let me help you out with jack.
為了Haley
For haley.
Garcia查到了些東西
Garcia's got something.
我簡直是個天才 看看我做了什麼
I'm a real genius 'cause this is what i di.
我從GPS系統堿d到了行程日誌
i took the travel logs from the gps sysms,
把他們的所有行程 覆蓋到地理側寫上 得出了書面追蹤查不到的信息
Overlaid their routes againsthe geographical profile to reveal what the paper trail could not.
是什麼呢?
Which was?
Erika Silverman是唯一個沒有去過 任何可能引來殺身之禍的酒吧 音樂會
While erika silverman is the only victim who didn't visit a private club, a concert,
或者什麼惟妙餐廳的受害者
Or go to a fancy restaurant in the days leading upo her death,
但週二 她卻在Cheekwood的 植物園塈b了一陣
She did spend a couple of hours at cheekwood botanical gardens on tuesday.
Garcia 其他的受害者也去過那個公園?
Garcia, did either of the other victims go to the park?
- 沒有 - 那我不覺得和這案子有什麼關繫了
- No. - I don't know if it's relevant, then.
當她的導航系統直線導航時 就有關聯了
It is when her navigation system reads in a straight line.
上班 回家 上班 回家 我認為她都沒走出過屋子
To work, back home, to work, back home. I don't think she ever left her house.
連生活日用她都要送貨上門
She even had her groceries delivered.
週二時她在做什麼?
What washe doi on tuesday?
一起查查吧
Let's find out.
人都到哪兒去了?
Where is everybody?
JJ和Reid追著一條線索查呢 Prentiss正在和Kaminski警官重新檢查
Well, jj and reid are checking on a lead, and prentiss is recanvassing with detective kaminski.
很好 那我們能聊聊了
Good. Then wcan talk.
Rossi...
這是他的團隊
It's his team.
我不會成為阻礙的
I'm not gonna stand in the way of that.
- 不一定會像你說的 - 什麼意思?
- It might not come to that. - What do you mean?
Strauss為他提供了退休的機會
Strauss offered him retirement.
他不會接受的
He'll never accept it.
不要這麼肯定 這份工作犧牲了他的妻子
Don't be so sure. This job cost him his wife.
很久以前就發生了
It cost him that a long time ago.
這就是為什麼 他不會再犧牲他的兒子了
Which is why he won't let it cost him his son.
你認為他會怎麼做?
What do you think he'll do?
我怎麼想不重要
It doesn't matter what i think.
重要的是如果他回來了 你願意卸任麼?
What matters is whether you'll be willing to step down if he comes back.
或者是在他不願意回來時繼任
Or step up if heoesn't.
我會按Hotch需要的去做 他已經失去太多了
I'm gonna do whatever hotch needs me to do. He's lost enough.
Rossi 介意過來下嗎? 我有點東西要給你看看
Hey, rossi. You mind coming here for second? I want to throw something at you.
我們對兇手的側寫表明 他最近經歷了失去
We profiled that our unsub recently experienced a loss as well.
失去了他深愛的人 或許是和被害者 有著相同背景的的深褐髮色女性
A loved one. Probably a brunette who ran in the same circles as his victi.
對
Right.
如果愛情並不是他唯一失去的呢?
What if love wasn't the only loss?
我們這樣假設 是因為兇手能輕易地 跟蹤受害人的上層生活
I mean, we assumed that because our unsub could so easily navigate our victims' upscale world
說明他很有可能和受害者 有著相同的收入來源
That he most likely shared the same financial resources as his victims.
因為他的教養 他優雅的舉止
Because of his upbringing, his sophisticated behavior.
但是這種行為舉止是根深蒂固的 就是一種習慣
But that behavior is ingrained in him. It's habit.
是他從小就學到的 不是長大了才會的
It something he would have learned as a child, not as an adt.
如果他並沒有經濟獨立 但仍在試圖維持他的社會地位
If he didn't have financial independence but were still trying to keep up his social status,
他的資金會大量流失
He'd be hemorrhaging funds.
我們查錯方向了Rossi
We've been looking at this the wrong way, rossi.
我們調查了女傭 園丁 清潔泳池的 能進入房子的每一個人
We vetted the maids, the gardeners, the pool cleaners, anyone who had access to the houses,
但還有哪個人能不引人注意地 進入上流社會的圈子?
But who else might go unnoticed in a privileged society?
這堿OGarcia
Garcia here.
Garcia 檢查下 每個受害者死前一個星期
Garcia, eck employee records at each of the venues
所去場所的員工記錄
the victims visited in the week prior to their dth.
查找那些入不敷出
Look f men spending beyond their means.
負債纍纍的人 Garcia
A guy who's racked up a lot of debt, garcia.
注意車子 服飾等不符合他收入水平的東西
Look at cars, wardrobes, something that does not fit their current income level.
可能是在提供獎學金的私人學校 接受的教育
A scholarship-funded private school education maybe.
正如你們所見 公園能吸引各種遊人
As you can see the park attracts a variety of patrons.
老夫老妻 散步的人 旅行團
Older couples, walkers, tour groups.
我們會在上面的草坪 不定期的舉行婚禮或者是演唱會
We'll hold an occasional wedding or concert sers on our upper lawn.
上個星期二有什麼活動嗎?
Did you have any events here past tuesday?
週二
Tuesday.
4點到7點之間我們舉行了一場社團募捐
Oh, we had a corporate fund-raiser between 4:00 and 7:00.
就是Erika Silverman在場的時候
That's when erika sierman was here.
要讓高跟鞋女士們來這兒參加活動 簡直比強行推銷還難
An event up here would be a hard sell for women in heels.
我們大部分活動 會僱傭服務人員 把車開回公園底部
well,Most of our prate events hire valets to drive the cars down to the base of the park
她們就不用徒步上山了
So they don't have to hiket up the hill.
誰會有機會拿到你的鑰匙然後消失?
Who has acce to your keys but goes unseen?
而且有機會接觸GPS定位系統
And your gps.
銷售商們甚至在你離開停車場之前
Dealerships program your home address into thnavigation system
就在導航系統中設定了你的家庭住址
before your car even leaves the lot.
他通過路線導航直接到了她家門口 靠鑰匙進了門
He had turn by turn directions straight to her front door and the keys to get m inside.
謝謝你... Joe
Thank you... Joe.
請輸入目的地
**********
帶我回家
********
Culpepper服務公司接手了週二的募捐活動...
Culpepper valet company handled the fund-raiser on tuesday, and...
也是這家公司和Heminger經常去的 旅館有過大堂服務合約
E same company had contracts with the hot lounge thanheminger frequented
還有Melissa Johnson所在的鄉村俱樂部
And the country club melissa johnson was a member at.
這就是我們要找的聯繫了
That's our connection.
JJ 讓Rossi和Prentiss去接那個公司的老闆
Jj, get rossi and prentiss to pick up the owner.
馬上
Right away.
好吧寶貝 和我聊聊
All right, baby girl, talk to me.
我需要員工記錄和這個週末 與Culpepper公司有合約的場館名單
I need employee records and a list of venues that culpepper contracted out to this weekend.
哦親愛的 查查你的郵件 60秒前就送到你的收件箱去了
Oh, sug, check your email. It hit your inbox 60 seconds ago.
謝謝 Penelope
Thanks, penelope.
好吧 Culpeer本週末與3個場館簽定了合同 有兩個是在今天
All right, culpeer contracted out to 3 venues this weekend, 2 today.
我們今天說不定能抓他個現行
We might be able to catch this guy in action.
除非他已經盯上了下一個受害者
Unless he's already with another victim.
我們尋找的兇手有可能在週二 被分配到Cheekwood公園
The man we're looking for would have been assigned to cheekwood park on tuesday.
等會兒 讓我嗯 查查名冊
Hold o let me, uh, pull the roster.
我們那天有6個人在場
Ok, we had 6 guys at tt site on that day.
他一定很少犯錯
He would have had very few if any disciplinary citings.
他很體面 看起來十分有紳士風度
He's proper. He appears to have had a gentlemanly upbringing.
他十分的浪漫 經常談論女人 愛情
He's a romantic. Heould have talked about women and love frequently.
他有可能才結束一段長期的戀情 或者失去了親近的人
He might have just ended a long-term relationship or lost someone close to him.
Belser  Joe Belser 他和他女朋友 他們分手了
Belser. Joe belser. Him and his girl, they bro up.
- 那是什麼時候? - 幾個星期以前 他們都訂婚了
- When was tt? - A few weeks ago. They were engaged.
你知道發生什麼了嗎?
Do you know what hapned?
他愛她 愛得神魂顛倒
He was head over heels inove with her.
而她卻和伴郎睡覺了
And she was sleeping with the best man.
經理說Belser在沃納街會所輪值
The manager said belser picked up a shift at the vonner street lounge.
好的 我們正往那趕
Yeah, we're headed there right now.
特警會和我們在Belser的公寓會合
Ok. Swat's gonna meet us at belser's apartment.
Garcia 查到什麼其他 關於Belser的資料嗎?
Garcia, did you find anything else on belser?
好的 他拿獎學金上了 南查爾斯頓的預科
Ok. He attended southern charleston preparatory academy on scholarship
他父母6年前死於一場遊艇事故
his parents died in a boating accident 6 years ago.
Belser炒股輸光了繼承的遺產 而從那以後
Belser lost his inheritance in thetock market, and since then,
他就入不敷出 靠借大量 根本無力償還的債度日
He has been racking up debt faster than he can pay it off.
他曾與時事雜誌編輯 Rose Smith訂婚 直到6周前...
He was engaged to society magazine editorose smith until 6 weeks ago...
婚事取消
When it was called off.
還有 連教堂的錢都已經付過了
And the chapel was already paid for.
所以 他花掉了自己所有的積蓄 好讓自己生活在未婚妻的世界
So he spent his entire savings trying to live in the world of his fiancee.
她則是 他與他從小到大 成長的社會的最後一絲聯繫
E was his lifeline the society he'd grown up in.
最後只落得人才兩空 身無分文收場
Only to have her leave him and wind up penniless.
嘿Garcia 我想Belser的車上 沒裝"Lo-Jack"防盜系統 是吧?
Hey, garcia, i don't suppe belser's car has a lo-jack system on it, does it?
沒 沒那麼幸運 小神童 我需要潛在受害者的名字
no.No such luck, boy wonder. Need potential victims' names.
- 我們會再和你聯繫的 - 好的
- We'll get back to you. - Ok.
FBI 開門!
Fb open up!
Joe Belser 我們是FBI! 如果你在堶 趕快現身!
Joe belser, fbi! If you're in there, identify yourself!
- 這埵w全 - 安全
- It's clear here. - Clear.
嘿  嗯...我想我發現 玫瑰花瓣的含義了
Hey, uh, i think i fod the meaning of the rose petals.
- 看看這些 - 開車庫門裝置?
- Look at these. - Garage door openers?
環球開車庫門裝置
Iversal garage door eners.
這就解決了複製鑰匙的問題
This solves the problem of having to copy the key.
有些車主聰明到會使用傭人鑰匙
Somerivers are smart enough to use a valet key,
但沒有人想到隨身帶個開車庫門裝置
But no one thinks to take a garage door opener with them.
他就是這麼進到 Melissa Johnson的房子堛
That's how he got into melissa johnson's house.
我們只在車庫門內側找到了指紋
We only found ints on the interior garage door.
我們以為 那是他在把狗 挪到車庫時留下的
We thought it was from he moved the dog into the garage.
很少會有人想到 要鎖住 一扇緊鎖大門堶悸漯
People rarely think to lock a door that lies beyond anothelocked door.
Reid 他不在這
Reid. He'sot here.
一名漂亮的深色頭髮女子 40歲上下
A beautiful brunette, late 30s, early 40s.
她可能會開一輛高檔SUV或轎車
She would have been driving a high-class suv or sedan.
她只買高端的東西
She only buys high-end.
沒有? 謝謝你
No? Ank you.
- VIP? - 肯定是
- Vip? - definitely.
讓我查一下登記記錄
Let me check the register logs.
這是今晚在我們VIP區 消費的所有客人名單
this is a list of all of our customers who de charges in our vip section tonight.
他們都有專屬的服務員
They have their own attendant.
15人堨u有6人是女性
15 names. Only 6 were women.
- Garcia 我們需要你 - 你有啥線索?
- Garcia, we need you. - Whatcha got?
過去3小時內在沃納街會所 使用過信用卡的6個人的名字
All right, 6 names used credit rds at the vonner street lounge in the past 3 hours.
Jennifer Keteln  Kiegan Murphy Heather Aldridge
Jennifer keteln, kiegan murphy, heather aldridge, meg natraj, ann herron, d katie gotshall.
Meg Natraj  Ann Herron  Katie Gotshall
好的 我正將財務記錄與 地理側寫進行交叉比對
Ok, i'm cross-referencing the geographical profile with financial records.
哦 這三個看起來沒事 而有一個是深色頭髮
Oh, these 3 look good, and one a brunette.
她叫Ann Herron 住在派爾街431號
Her name is n herron. She lives at 431 pyle street.
我們找到他了
We got him.
甜心
Sweetheart.
- 我們會幸福地在一起的 - 不!
- We are going to be happy together. - No!
你不希望能夠這樣發展嗎?
Don't you want this to work out?
- 回答我! - 不!
- Answer me! - No!
Annie! 我努力讓今晚 變成一個神奇的夜晚!
Annie! I'm trying to make this a magical night!
不! 不!
No! No!
你把這一切都毀了!
You ruined ts!
FBI! 放下!
Fbi! Put it down!
沒事了 你會沒事的
It's ok. You're gonna be ok.
幻想結束了
Fantasy's over.
你就是那麼對她們的? 你打她們 好讓她們不出聲
Is that what you did to the you hit them to shut them up
然後 強迫她們服從你病態的妄想?
And then forced them to play along with your sick delusion?
我愛她們
I love them.
你終於要遇到你的靈魂伴侶了 Joe 在大牢
You're finally gonna meet your soul mate, joe. Prison.
只是 你不能像對那些女性一樣 任意擺佈他了
Only you'rnot gonna be able to push him around the way you did thoswomen.
而當夜半時分 他找上你的時候
And when he comes for you in the middle of the night,
當你最不希望的時候 幫我個忙吧
When you're least expecting it, you do me a favor.
服從他吧
Play along.
她怎麼樣了?
How is she?
她很堅強 她會挺過來的
She's strong. She'll make it.
但經歷過這樣的事 必定是會留下傷痕的
But you don't survive something like that without scars.
傷痕會提醒我們曾經的處境
Scars remind us where we've been.
但卻不一定要由它們 支配我們未來的境遇
They don't have to dictate where we're goin.
我有種預感 會在這找到你
i had a feeling i'd find you here.
你告訴她了嗎?
Have you told her yet?
告訴她什麼?
Lder what?
你要回組堥
That you're coming back to theeam.
跟壞人鬥智鬥勇是你的本性
That fightinthe bad guys is who you are.
我不用告訴她
I don't have to tell her.
她早就知道了
She already knows.
"將要直面的 與已成過往的
"what lies behind us and at lies before us are tiny matters
較之深埋於我們內心的 皆為微末"
compared wt lies within us."
拉爾夫·瓦爾多·愛默生
Ralph waldo emerson.
犯罪心理 第五季 第10集
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode10 The Slave of Duty